[ {
  "num" : "1",
  "question" : "가는 날이",
  "answer" : "장날",
  "options" : [ "절받기", "축제", "장날", "오는날" ]
}, {
  "num" : "2",
  "question" : "가는 말이 고와야",
  "answer" : "오는 말이 곱다",
  "options" : [ "오는 말이 곱다", "무시당한다", "개구리", "성품이 좋다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "3",
  "question" : "가랑비에 옷 젖는 줄",
  "answer" : "모른다",
  "options" : [ "모른다", "안다", "알까?", "알았다." ]
}, {
  "num" : "4",
  "question" : "가제는",
  "answer" : "게 편",
  "options" : [ "닭 편", "새우 등 터진다", "맛있다", "게 편" ]
}, {
  "num" : "5",
  "question" : "개구리 올챙이 적",
  "answer" : "생각 못한다",
  "options" : [ "귀엽다", "생각 못한다", "어둡다", "게 편" ]
}, {
  "num" : "6",
  "question" : "개천에서",
  "answer" : "용 난다",
  "options" : [ "승천한다", "이무기", "용 난다", "방울 달기" ]
}, {
  "num" : "7",
  "question" : "고래 싸움에",
  "answer" : "새우 등 터진다",
  "options" : [ "맞는다", "이득 본다", "크게 다친다", "새우 등 터진다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "8",
  "question" : "고양이 목에",
  "answer" : "방울 달기",
  "options" : [ "방울 달기", "태산", "장날", "게 편" ]
}, {
  "num" : "9",
  "question" : "금강산도",
  "answer" : "식후경",
  "options" : [ "배고프다", "부채질 한다", "식후경", "게 편" ]
}, {
  "num" : "10",
  "question" : "꿩 대신",
  "answer" : "닭",
  "options" : [ "천 리 간다", "약 준다", "닭", "고양이" ]
}, {
  "num" : "11",
  "question" : "남의 손의 떡은",
  "answer" : "커 보인다",
  "options" : [ "맛있다", "빼앗기", "먹기", "커 보인다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "12",
  "question" : "낫 놓고 기역 자도",
  "answer" : "모른다",
  "options" : [ "말로 받는다", "생각 못한다", "먹기", "모른다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "13",
  "question" : "누워서",
  "answer" : "떡 먹기",
  "options" : [ "떡 먹기", "죽 먹기", "방울 달기", "게임하기" ]
}, {
  "num" : "14",
  "question" : "도둑이 제 발",
  "answer" : "저리다",
  "options" : [ "저리다", "아프다", "힘들다", "더 크다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "15",
  "question" : "돌다리도 두들겨 보고",
  "answer" : "건너라",
  "options" : [ "건너라", "가라", "뛰어라", "새우 등 터진다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "16",
  "question" : "되로 주고",
  "answer" : "말로 받는다",
  "options" : [ "말로 받는다", "소로 받는다", "떡 먹기", "절받기" ]
}, {
  "num" : "17",
  "question" : "등잔 밑이",
  "answer" : "어둡다",
  "options" : [ "밝다", "어둡다", "어두컴컴하다", "환하다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "18",
  "question" : "모난 돌이 정",
  "answer" : "맞는다",
  "options" : [ "맞는다", "없다", "떨어진다", "더 크다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "19",
  "question" : "바늘 가는 데",
  "answer" : "실 간다",
  "options" : [ "실 간다", "어디인가", "골무 간다", "장날" ]
}, {
  "num" : "20",
  "question" : "바늘 도둑이",
  "answer" : "소도둑 된다",
  "options" : [ "소도둑 된다", "말로 받는다", "절받기", "행복하다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "21",
  "question" : "배보다 배꼽이",
  "answer" : "더 크다",
  "options" : [ "더 작다", "더 크다", "방울 달기", "약 준다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "22",
  "question" : "발 없는 말이",
  "answer" : "천 리 간다",
  "options" : [ "천 리 간다", "소도둑 된다", "슬퍼", "빠르다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "23",
  "question" : "백지장도",
  "answer" : "맞들면 낫다",
  "options" : [ "맞들면 낫다", "장날", "약 준다", "무겁다다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "24",
  "question" : "병 주고",
  "answer" : "약 준다",
  "options" : [ "약 준다", "병 준다", "떡 먹기", "모른다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "25",
  "question" : "불난 집에",
  "answer" : "부채질 한다",
  "options" : [ "방울 달기", "부채질 한다", "신고 하기", "물 뿌리기" ]
}, {
  "num" : "26",
  "question" : "소 잃고",
  "answer" : "외양간 고친다",
  "options" : [ "울기", "외양간 고친다", "떡 먹기", "슬퍼하다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "27",
  "question" : "우물 안",
  "answer" : "개구리",
  "options" : [ "개구리", "올챙이", "지렁이", "호랑이" ]
}, {
  "num" : "28",
  "question" : "울며 겨자",
  "answer" : "먹기",
  "options" : [ "먹기", "버리기", "치우기", "정리하기" ]
}, {
  "num" : "29",
  "question" : "엎드려",
  "answer" : "절받기",
  "options" : [ "절받기", "약받기", "인사한다다", "말로 받는다" ]
}, {
  "num" : "30",
  "question" : "티끌 모아",
  "answer" : "태산",
  "options" : [ "티끌", "태산", "말로 받는다", "닭" ]
} ]